# **Stephen D'Arcy**

## **Business Analyst**

Email sdarcy29@hotmail.com Phone 086-7239007

**LinkedIn** <u>linkedin.com/in/stephen-darcy-38987167</u>

I have worked within various teams in the financial services sector for the past 8 years. I have a real interest in technology and how it can be utilized in today's world. I am currently undertaking a Diploma in Software Development which encompasses HTML,CSS JavaScript, and Python among other technologies.

## **Work History**

11-2019 - present

#### **Business Analyst change management**

## Citibank Ireland, Dublin

- Perform in-depth evaluation to identify and resolve complex problems.
- Perform data analysis on client Ids in production environments.
- To interpret business requirements from across the business and implement change requests.
- Write and update business requirements documents and statement of requirements.
- Perform PVT and UAT testing as and where required in the lifecycle of the change request.
- Write PVT files in H2H and XML format for PVT testing.
- Influence decisions through advice and counsel as well as facilitate services to others.
- Liaises with multiple teams across the Operations department.
- Assume informal and formal leadership role within the team.

03-2018 - 10-2019

#### Senior sanctions compliance analyst

## Citibank Ireland, Dublin

- Analyse comparative data, prepare, and present regional and global reports related to sanctions risk assessments, and monitoring of sanctions related issues and escalations with senior management and global partners.
- Support a specialised team of Independent Compliance Risk Management (ICRM) officers responsible for program execution activities.
- Support all EMEA businesses by acting in an advisory sanction's compliance capacity, acting as the Level 3 escalation point for complex sanctions compliance escalations including transaction monitoring, mergers, and acquisitions among other instruments.
- Contributes to the design and maintenance of a comprehensive written ICRM Sanctions Framework (standards and policies)
- Monitors adherence to Citi's Global Sanctions Policy and relevant procedures; is up

to date on key Sanctions regulatory changes, key enforcement actions and related industry trends.

- Overseas adherence to procedures and processes, to ensure compliance with policies ensuring that front line units meet required standards.
- Interacts with relevant teams to raise awareness of Sanctions trends, emerging issues, remedial actions, or enhancements to the program.
- Draft and edit sanctions-related reference materials and participate in sanctions training programs.

06-2016 - 03-2018

#### Financial crime and AML and sanctions officer

## AIB Group, Dublin

- Ensure all 2nd level queries and payments are fully investigated and ensure there are no sanction breaches or compliance issues.
- Liaise with internal & external stakeholders regarding Financial Crime matters
- To answer all mails in a timely and accurate manner.
- To make sure all internal systems are regularly checked on OFAC, EUR-LEX AND HM Treasury updates
- Capture and record accurate investigative findings to support decision taken.
- Investigating accounts/policies/products where potentially suspicious account activity is identified.
- Use several systems to exclude potential persons and entities for matches against various world and European sanctions and compliance lists.

07-2015 - 07-2016

#### **Risk / AML Payments Investigator**

## Bank of Ireland, Dublin

- Ensure sanction matches/ suspicious activity is identified in a timely manner.
- Liaise with internal & external stakeholders regarding Financial Crime matters
- Capture and record accurate investigative findings to support decision taken.
- Investigating accounts/policies/products where potentially suspicious account activity is identified.
- Gather intelligence and investigate potentially sanctioned payments/suspicious activity.
- Provide day-to-day support to the Manager in assisting on-going compliance with regulatory requirements.
- Test training courses regarding sanctions awareness and AML protocols.
- Some supervisory roles Delegating daily tasks Preparing daily and monthly stats for manager meetings Assisting with team Rota's.

09-2013 - 07-2015

Business online (several positions held as

below)

Bank of Ireland, Dublin

**Customer Service Agent** 

- Answered calls from business customers regarding queries on their account.
- Assisted with logging in to the business online system.
- Advised on technical procedures to help restore online functionality for customers.

#### Query management team

- Locate missing payments for customers and advise on the status of the payments.
- Advise customers on the reason for payments being returned or rejected.
- Making follow up calls to customers to issue passwords or log in details.
- Working with other payment departments to assure all proper documentation has been sent out to customers.
- Assisted with general troubleshooting and access issues for staff surrounding annual leave and the SAP payment platform.

## Business on Line 2nd Level Technical Support

- Lead a small team that would follow up on logged calls from customers who were continuing to have difficulties logging on to the online system after 1st level help.
- Compile reports from the customer management systems on workload for management.

## Business online Fraud Helpdesk

- Extract information from International and SEPA payment reports to locate possible fraudulent activity.
- Checking business online payments for group operations to verify their authenticity.
- Contacting customers where their account has been blocked due to possible viruses on their laptops/P. C's.
- Reporting all possible fraud to the relevant departments as well as putting recalls on the funds.
- Some supervisory roles Delegating daily tasks Preparing daily and monthly stats for manager meetings.

#### **Education**

09-2013 - 01-2016

Financial Advice, Qualified Financial Advisor

*Institute of Banking/UCD , Dublin* 

12-2018 - 01-2020

Business analytics, database design and statistics, Level 8 Special Purpose Award

Galway/Mayo institute of technology, Online

08-2021 - present

Software Development, Diploma in Software Development

## The Code Institute, Online

## Skills

HTML and CSS
JavaScript/Python – Beginner.
SQL - MTA: Database Fundamentals - Certified 2021
Data analysis
Problem solving
Microsoft Office
Advanced Excel

# **Projects**

GitHub - <a href="https://github.com/darco31">https://github.com/darco31</a>

HTML / CSS - <a href="https://github.com/darco31/theCupCakeFactory">https://github.com/darco31/theCupCakeFactory</a> This site can be found here: <a href="https://github.com/darco31/theCupCakeFactory">The CupCake Factory</a>

JavaScript - <a href="https://github.com/darco31/P2---JS-game">https://github.com/darco31/P2---JS-game</a>
This site can be found here: <a href="Rock-Paper-Scissors-Lizard-Spock">Rock-Paper-Scissors-Lizard-Spock</a>

Python - <a href="https://github.com/darco31/The-Great-Castle-Escape">https://github.com/darco31/The-Great-Castle-Escape</a>
The live deployed application can be found here <a href="https://github.com/darco31/The-Great-Castle-Escape">The live deployed application can be found here The Great Castle Escape</a>